<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IoT on Djalal Harouni</title>
    <link>https://djalal.opendz.org/tags/iot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IoT on Djalal Harouni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2021, Djalal Harouni; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://djalal.opendz.org/tags/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>eBPF: Block Linux Fileless Payload &#34;Malware&#34; Execution with BPF LSM</title>
      <link>https://djalal.opendz.org/post/ebpf-block-linux-fileless-payload-execution-with-bpf-lsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://djalal.opendz.org/post/ebpf-block-linux-fileless-payload-execution-with-bpf-lsm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Due to the security features that Linux offers, like booting directly into a readonly filesystem, making filesystems readonly at runtime for apps and containers, some attacks have been using what is known as &amp;quot;fileless binary execution&amp;quot; to avoid such protections, and gain the ability to execute binaries directly from the memory without touching or leaving traces on the disk.
 From Wikipedia &amp;quot;Fileless malware is a variant of computer related malicious software that exists exclusively as a computer memory-based artifact i.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eBPF Summit 2021 - Talk: BPF to bridge Cloud and IoT Linux Security</title>
      <link>https://djalal.opendz.org/post/ebpf-summit-2021-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://djalal.opendz.org/post/ebpf-summit-2021-talk/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the eBPF Summit 2021, I gave a talk about how to take advantage of eBPF to try to bridge some cloud and IoT security features.
 My Talk can be found here: BPF to bridge Cloud and IoT Linux Security on youtube
All eBPF Summit 2021 here: eBPF Summit 2021 Youtube Channel
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All systems go Conference - Modern deployment for Embedded Linux and IoT Talk</title>
      <link>https://djalal.opendz.org/post/modern-deployment-for-embedded-linux-and-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://djalal.opendz.org/post/modern-deployment-for-embedded-linux-and-iot/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Userspace Linux Conference All Systems Go! 2017 videos and talks are now available online.
My talk &amp;quot;Modern Deployment for Embedded Linux and IoT&amp;quot; is available here:
Video - Slides
All video talks are here
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardening Linux-based IoT systems</title>
      <link>https://djalal.opendz.org/post/hardening-linux-based-iot-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://djalal.opendz.org/post/hardening-linux-based-iot-systems/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;TL;DR: In Linux kernel and as part of the Kernel Self Protection Project we are pushing for new lightweight security mechanisms. On top of that, in systemd we are implementing new lightweight container mechanisms that target Embedded Linux and IoT. Our goal is to make it easy to deploy Secure Embedded Linux and IoT systems.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
